imccinemas.ie 2019-04-04

# Privacy Notice

**Privacy Notice**

**_Introduction_**

At IMC Cinema Group, your privacy and data protection rights are very important to IMC. 

IMC are committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring that any personal data collected is collected in accordance with the Irish and EU Data Protection Legislation. 

Data Protection is the safeguarding of the privacy rights of individuals in relation to the processing of personal data, in both paper and electronic format. 

IMC is the data controller of your information, under the Irish laws governing privacy, if your residential address is in the Island of Ireland. 

**_Purpose of this policy_**

This policy outlines how IMC Cinema Group collects, stores and uses any information that you provide IMC when visiting our website or purchasing our products and services. 

By using our services, you acknowledge that IMC will collect and use information as described in this Data Protection Policy. 

**_GDPR_**

The IMC Data Protection Policy is in compliance with the GDPR. 

The EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) replaces the Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC and was designed to harmonize data privacy laws across Europe, to protect and empower all EU citizens data privacy and to reshape the way organizations across the region approach data privacy. 

**_Personal Information_**

This section will outline what data IMC are obtaining from our customers while using our services. 

In order to process your booking, we collect personal details from you. This information is treated with the highest standards of security. 

When making a booking online we ask for your name, email and telephone number. Once you proceed to payment, we then ask for your credit card details in order to make the booking. 

These credit card details are encrypted. This means that when a credit account holder makes a purchase with their card, the information such as the account number are scrambled by an algorithm. The intent is to make it impossible for a third party to access that information. 

We also collect information from you when you contact IMC regarding queries or complaints. If you contact the IMC customer services team or any of our cinemas via email, social media, or any other forms, we may store this information and share the information you provide us with in order to provide a better customer experience. 

When you register for myIMC we ask for: 

  * Name
  * Address
  * Email 
  * Date of birth
  * Gender

These details are collected for the purpose of identifying each separate customer as they log in to their account. 

This information is also used to notify customers when changes in bookings/cancellations occur. 

When you browse our website or use our mobile app we may collect: 

  * Information about your online purchase
  * Information about your browsing behaviour 
  * Information about your previous visits to our website

**_Terms under which IMC processes data_**

  * _Consent_ \- IMC will process data if they have been granted direct consent from the data subject.
  * _Contract-_ IMC will process data when it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is a party.
  * _Legal basis_ \- IMC will process data when it is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation.
  * _Protection_ \- IMC will process data to protect the vital interests of the data subject or another individual. 
  * _Public interest_ \- IMC will process data when it is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official duty.
  * _Data controller_ \- IMC will process data when it is necessary for the legitimate interests of the data controller, unless such interests are overridden by the rights/interest of the data subject.

**_Why we collect personal data and how we use it_**

There are multiple reasons why we collect personal data from our customers: 

  * _To manage customer online accounts / gift cards / loyalty cards_
  * _To make general bookings for customers and give customer refunds_
  * _To contact/interact our customers_
  * _To improve overall customer experience_
  * _To help develop and improve our services_
  * _Queries/Complaints_
  * _To help us solve website or server issues_

When you create an IMC account we ask for your personal data in order to differentiate you from other customers. This keeps your account separate and private; meaning no one else can access/use it. 

The cinemas keep a record of loyalty cards and gift cards purchased by customers for company accounts, records purposes and to deal with customer queries. 

We collect your personal details/credit card details in order to process your online booking, and in rare circumstances to issue a refund. 

We collect email/telephone numbers so that we can contact customers when there is a change in the film schedule or an event has occurred that may affect our services. 

We collect data about our customers in order to give our customers the best experience possible. The more we learn about our customers, the better we can serve them. 

We rely on the use of personal data for market research and internal research purposes. We use this data to improve the overall customer experience. 

If a customer makes a query or a complaint to our customer services, the information given will be stored by IMC and may be shared by the head office to the cinema it is referencing in order to investigate the complaint. 

We may use the data we collect from you while using our website to solve any issues that can arise with our servers or the IMC website. 

**_Who we share information with_**

IMC Cinema Group may share your information under certain circumstances: 

  * We may need to share information in order to comply with any legal obligations brought to our attention. 
  * We may be requested by law enforcement to comply with any court orders or search warrants. 
  * If IMC are involved in any mergers or acquisitions, or if the business is being purchased or sold, we may need to share information with potential purchasers/vendors and/or company advisors.
  * If you have entered a competition on our social media platforms, this may require us to share your information with a third party in order to avail of the prize.

**_Website_** ****

By visiting the IMC the website and providing us with any personal data/information, by email or any other form, you acknowledge that you have read and understood the IMC Data Protection Policy and you agree to the terms and conditions of this policy on how IMC collects, uses and stores your data. 

**_Identification_**

When making a booking, online or on-site, we may ask your age and for identification. The reason we require this information is so that we can adhere to the age-regulations set in place by the **** Irish Film Classification Office. ****

We also ask your age when registering for myIMC or making online bookings, as our online services are only available to users over the age of 15 years of age. By using this service you are confirming that you are over the age of 15 years of age. 

**_The use of ‘Cookies’_**

Cookies are small files which are stored on a user's computer. They are designed to hold a modest amount of data specific to a particular client and website, and can be accessed either by the web server or the client computer. This allows the server to deliver a page tailored to a particular user, or the page itself can contain some script which is aware of the data in the cookies. 

The IMC Cinema Group website uses ‘Cookies’. When you click into our website you will see a message: 

‘By using this website, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information on cookies see our [cookie policy.](https://www.imccinemas.ie/Terms)’ 

If you wish, you can set your browser to prevent it from accepting cookies. 

**_Location tracking_**

IMC has location tracking on their website which can identify where you are based on the GPS on your phone. IMC only has access to this information once the data subject has the ‘location’ turned on on their device.IMC collect this information to provide a better user experience. This information will only be used by IMC and not shared with any third party marketing companies. 

**_Third party links_**

The IMC Cinemas website contains links to third party websites such as YouTube, Facebook, Twitter, Indeed, and Instagram. As the customer chooses whether to click on these third party links, IMC is not liable for problems that may occur while visiting these third party sites. 

IMC is a separate entity and is not responsible for the Data Protection Policy that is in place on those third party websites. You should keep updated on these third party websites Privacy Policies. 

**_Security_**

Security is of upmost importance to IMC and we have procedures in place to protect all your personal data, and prevent unauthorised access or misuse. 

Any data traveling through the internet is authenticated and encrypted. 

_Our website is PCI compliant_ : The Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard ( **PCI**  DSS) applies to IMC Cinema Group as it accepts credit card payments. As IMC accepts card payment, and stores, processes and transmits cardholder data, IMC hosts the data securely with a PCI compliant hosting provider.

_IMC Cinema Group uses SSL Technology_ : Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) is standard security technology for establishing an encrypted link between a server and a client. SSL allows sensitive information such as credit card numbers and login credentials to be transmitted securely. 

_HTTPS:_ IMC employs web server certificates signed by Thawte. The ‘https’ in the navigation bar indicates that IMC has a private encrypted and authenticated connection to the website and that no third party users should be able to intercept the web pages you are browsing. 

**_Passwords_**

Any passwords created by the user on the IMC Cinema Group website are 'hashed' and ‘salted’, which is more advanced than just encryption. A hash is a one-way function which means that there is no function to reverse or undo a hash, preventing a password from being guessed. 

You, as the data subject, are responsible for keeping your password safe and confidential. 

Any IMC Cinema Group company computer holding customer data is password protected and can only be accessed by authorized personnel. 

**_Card payments_**

Any credit or debit card payments that are processed on our website are not processed by IMC Cinemas, but by our third part card payment provider. 

No credit cards are processed or stored by IMC Cinema Group. 

**_Privacy Policy changes_**

IMC has the right to change and amend this Privacy Policy as we see fit. Data subjects, customers, suppliers and employees should check our website regularly to keep up to date with the IMC Data Protection Policy. 

**_Your Rights_**

_Under the data protection act, data subjects have:_

The right to ask for a copy of any information we hold about you. 

The right to object to profiling 

The right to obtain a copy of their gathered personal data 

The right to be forgotten 

The right to request that your IMC account be closed and deleted 

If you need to change/delete any personal data that we hold, you can contact our customer services team on [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**_Our Rights_**

The limited company of IMC Cinema Group, including its directors, and staff members, will not be held liable for claims made against the company as a result of the use of personal information relating to any data subject. 

Please note IMC Cinema Group will also not be liable for any expenses such as losses or damages, emergencies, or legal fees that occur as a result of this information being compromised. 

**_Contact us_** ****

We welcome any feedback you may have. We will put every effort into correcting any action that may not comply with our privacy policy once we are made aware of such. 

_Contact us:_

[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#ee9e9c87988f8d97ae87838d8d87808b838f9dc0878b)

Astor House, 

29 Lower Georges Street, 

Dun Laoghaire, 

Co. Dublin 

**_Data Access Request_**

**_[click here to download form in PDF format](https://www.imccinemas.ie/Portals/0/arf.pdf?ver=2018-05-09-140356-607)  
_**
